<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on I-Fan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on I-Fan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-tw</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building Automated Hugo Content Pipeline with n8n and Claude AI</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s focus was on establishing an automated workflow using n8n to streamline the daily note generation process, integrating Claude AI for content enhancement and automatic Hugo site deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main objective was to eliminate manual steps in the daily note publishing workflow. Currently, the process involves manually transforming AI-processed notes into Hugo posts and handling repository updates. The solution leverages n8n to create an automated pipeline that reads local notes, enhances them with Claude AI, formats them for Hugo, and pushes changes to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Production-Ready Mac Mini M4 Development Environment</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:51:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When transitioning to a new development machine, especially one intended to serve as both a local workstation and a remote development server, the setup process requires careful planning. This article documents the complete configuration of a Mac mini M4 (24GB) as a full-featured development environment, focusing on remote accessibility, containerized services, and productivity automation through n8n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is clear: create a reliable, remotely accessible development hub that supports Go-based backend projects, database management, and workflow automation—all while maintaining clean separation between development tools and system configurations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>