<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>N8n on I-Fan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/tags/n8n/</link><description>Recent content in N8n on I-Fan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-tw</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/tags/n8n/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building n8n Automation Workflow for Hugo Blog Content Generation</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s focus was on establishing an automated n8n workflow to streamline the daily note generation process for Hugo blog posts. The goal was to eliminate manual steps in transforming raw development notes into polished blog content using AI assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="problem-statement"&gt;Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current workflow involves several manual steps that create friction in the content creation process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily notes require manual formatting and editing after AI processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo post creation involves repetitive file structure setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub deployment requires manual commits and pushes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution involves creating an n8n automation that takes raw daily notes, processes them through Claude AI, and automatically creates properly formatted Hugo posts with GitHub integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Production-Ready Mac Mini M4 Development Environment</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:51:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When transitioning to a new development machine, especially one intended to serve as both a local workstation and a remote development server, the setup process requires careful planning. This article documents the complete configuration of a Mac mini M4 (24GB) as a full-featured development environment, focusing on remote accessibility, containerized services, and productivity automation through n8n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is clear: create a reliable, remotely accessible development hub that supports Go-based backend projects, database management, and workflow automation—all while maintaining clean separation between development tools and system configurations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>