<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on I-Fan's Tech Blog</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on I-Fan's Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>zh-tw</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>N8N Automation Workflow for Hugo Content Generation</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025-11-25_note/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s focus was on building an automated workflow using N8N to streamline the daily note generation process for Hugo static site. The goal was to eliminate manual steps in converting AI-processed development notes into published Hugo posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-overview"&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main challenge was the repetitive manual process of taking daily development notes, processing them through AI (Claude), and then manually creating Hugo posts and pushing to GitHub. This workflow aimed to automate the entire pipeline from local note files to published content.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Setting Up a Production-Ready Mac Mini M4 Development Environment</title><link>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 22:51:55 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://ifan0927.github.io/my-tech-blog/posts/2025_11_24_note/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When transitioning to a new development machine, especially one intended to serve as both a local workstation and a remote development server, the setup process requires careful planning. This article documents the complete configuration of a Mac mini M4 (24GB) as a full-featured development environment, focusing on remote accessibility, containerized services, and productivity automation through n8n.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is clear: create a reliable, remotely accessible development hub that supports Go-based backend projects, database management, and workflow automation—all while maintaining clean separation between development tools and system configurations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>